Menu

* Search

Menu

Search

* * [\[email protected\]](https://www.science-sparks.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

[Home](https://www.science-sparks.com/) » Privacy Policy and Data Protection

Privacy Policy and Data Protection
==================================

Policy Updated 23rd May 2018

Wild Sparks Enterprises value and protect your privacy

This policy explains when and why we collect information about you, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.

We may change this Policy from time to time so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes. By using our website, you’re agreeing to be bound by this Policy.

Any questions regarding this Policy and our privacy practices should be sent by email to [\[email protected\]](https://www.science-sparks.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Who are we?
-----------

Science Sparks™ is an online education site founded in 2011 by Emma Vanstone. We are based in the UK but have contributing authors from around the world.

How we Collect Information About You
------------------------------------

Information is collected via log files, cookies, leaving comments on the site or subscribing to our newsletter.

What Information do we Collect About You
----------------------------------------

We collect information on your name, email address, website (if you leave this in a comment), IP address and the pages that you visited and when you visited them on the site.

How and Why we Track your Visit
-------------------------------

Like most websites around the world we use Google Analytics (GA) to process information about the number of visitors on our site, and their behaviour

We use this information to record the number of people using Science Sparks and to better understand where you discover our site (from social media, google or another site) and how you use it as well as to see how people move throughout the site.

GA records your approximate location down to town level, the type device you are using e.g. Mobile or Table, Name of device e.g. iPad or Samsung Galazy etc…, operating system e.g. Windows 10 or iOS and browser e.g. Firefox or Chrome none of this data can be used to identify you.

Google does record your IP address however, we don’t have access to this information and it modifies it so that you can not be identified specifically just the area that you are in.

### Google Analytics Demographics

We are committed to ensuring that our website contains content that is valuable and useful to our readers.

To help us with this we have implemented the Google analytics demographics and interest reporting features on our website.

These tools allow us to review anonymous data regarding the gender, age and interests of website visitors and adapt our website content to better reflect their needs.

Although this information is collected through your Google ad settings, it is not provided to us in a personally-identifiable format.

This means we cannot identify what information is about you, and we will not try to figure it out.

You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customise Google Display Network ads using the [Google Ad settings](https://adssettings.google.ca/anonymous?sig=ACi0TCim925cB07-7cpwU1t82Zih-cyZJ-z258Rhs2_ob_VD9-KN0PF7SNjosxPqWAnMkL5o3KkIzcaiKhInpLNrtrjGb3FOZ2AF3COImtlEVfU_oOnno0I&hl=en) or through the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

To do this Google Analytics uses a “cookie” on your machine read more about Cookies below.

Leaving a Comment on our Site
-----------------------------

We love feedback on all our activities so love it when people leave a comment.

To leave a comment you may leave it anonymously or leave a name, email address, website and comment.

We only use this information to identify you as the comment maker and do not pass this on to any third party.

Your email address will never be shown in the comment section of the site.

Your details will remain in the database unless we remove it or the article is removed from the site.

You may request that we delete the comment and remove you details at any time. Please email to ask for this to be carried out.

If you are under 16 you must obtain your parents permission before leaving a comment.

**IMPORTANT: In your comment you should avoid leaving information of a personal nature and it is recommended that you do this on any website you comment on.**

Subscriber Newsletter
---------------------

If you choose to join one of our regular newsletters via a sign up form then you email address is required so that you can be sent the emails.

Your data is collected and then passed to our Email Service Provider MailChimp.

You may unsubscribe at any time from our newsletters using the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email or you can email us and ask that you be removed.

We send emails 1 – 3 times a week and with our tracking try and make these as relevant to you as possible. From time to time we may include promotions for products.

Details that we hold including your name, email address and where you have visited will never be passed onto a Third Party.

Advertisements on Science Sparks™
---------------------------------

We use third party advertisements on Science Sparks™ to support our site.

* Google Double Click
* Ad Thrive

Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.

This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

Cookies
-------

Specifically cookies are used for:

* Our commenting system so that you don’t have to always enter you details
* Collect data as part of Google Analytics so that we can see who has visited our website

You can chose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in your browser.

However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

* Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on  www.rainydaymum.co.uk.
* Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to www.rainydaymum.co.uk and other sites on the Internet.
* You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – [https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads)

If you are Under 16
-------------------

Please obtain your parents permission before entering any personal information on Science Sparks, we are concerned with your privacy as much as an adults.

When we may transfer your personal data
---------------------------------------

We will not transfer your personal data unless we are under legal obligation to do so.

If you wish to be removed from our data
---------------------------------------

At any point you may ask that we remove your information from our systems. Please contact us via e-mail [\[email protected\]](https://www.science-sparks.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) with your requirements and we will do so within a month.

The same applies for what information we hold about you and can be identified as being about you.

Primary Sidebar
---------------

* [\[email protected\]](https://www.science-sparks.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

### What are you looking for?

Search

### Fill your inbox with science

#### Newsletter

Signup for weekly science in your inbox

You can unsubscribe anytime. For more details, review our Privacy Policy.

Opt in to receive news and updates.

Subscribe

Loading...

#### Thank you!

You have successfully joined our subscriber list.

Footer
------

### Newsletter

* [**Sign Up**!](https://dashboard.mailerlite.com/forms/635973/101582805567276814/share) for emails and updates

### Contact

* Services
* Media Kit
* FAQ

As an Amazon Associate I earn from qualifying purchases.

Copyright © 2024 Science Sparks - Wild Sparks Enterprises Ltd
